

# NICOLA RENNIE

Nicola Rennie is an academic and data scientist, passionate about using statistics to solve problems. She is currently a Lecturer in Health Data Science at Lancaster Medical School, working on time series analysis and applications related to health. Nicola also has experience in data science consultancy, and collaborates closely with external research partners.

# **Employment**

#### Lecturer in Health Data Science.

Lancaster University, Lancaster, UK. Apr 2022 - Present.

#### **Data Scientist**

Jumping Rivers, Remote, UK. Nov 2021 - Apr 2022.

#### **Mathematical Consultant**

Smith Institute, Oxford, UK. Aug 2021 - Nov 2021.

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

Lancaster University, Lancaster, UK. Oct 2018 - Jul 2021.

## **Education**

### PhD in Statistics and Operational Research

Lancaster University, Lancaster, UK. 2021

Thesis: Detecting demand outliers in transport systems

## **MRes in Statistics and Operational Research**

Lancaster University, Lancaster, UK. 2018

#### **BSc(Hons) in Mathematics**

University of St Andrews, St Andrews, UK. 2017

# Selected publications

### Analysing and visualising bike sharing demand with outliers.

N. Rennie, C. Cleophas, A. M. Sykulski, F. Dost

Discover Data. Volume 1, Issue 1. March 2023. doi.org/10.1007/s44248-023-00001-z

# Identifying and responding to outlier demand in revenue management

N. Rennie, C. Cleophas, A. M. Sykulski, F. Dost

*European Journal of Operational Research*. Volume 293, Issue 3, 16 September 2021, 1015-1030. doi.org/10.1016/j.ejor.2021.01.002

A full list of publications and conference presentations is available on my website: nrennie.rbind.io

## Notable awards

### Finalist of the 2021 Statistical Excellence Award for Early-Career Writing.

Significance and the RSS Young Statisticians Section. July 2021.

#### Nick Smith Prize for Research Excellence.

Lancaster University. August 2020.